所以我们将从幺半群开始。
So we're gonna start here with monoids.
我要定义我们所说的半组。
And I'm gonna define what we call a semi group.
如果您听说过或使用过半组，请举手。
Raise your hand if you've heard of a semi group or used it.
好的，我们有一个。
Okay, we got one.
好吧，幺半群怎么样，人们正在使用，很酷。
All right, how about monoids, people are using, cool.
所以，我们将从定义一个半组开始，让我们看一些例子。
So, we're gonna start by defining a semi group and let's look at some examples.
所以一加二，加三加六，其实并不重要。
So one plus two, plus three plus six, doesn't really matter.
这里发生的事情是我是否加括号无关紧要
What's happening here is it doesn't matter if I parenthesize
这些在右边或左边，我会得到相同的答案。
these ones in the right or the left first, I'll get the same answer.
因此，关联性再次发挥作用。
So again, associativity keeps coming into play.
所以加法是结合的，它也是封闭的。
So addition is associative, it also is closed.
因此，如果我添加一堆整数，我将永远无法通过加法打破整数。
So if I add a bunch of integers I can never break out of integers with addition.
我总是会得到整数，所以它在组合下关闭。
I'll always get integers back, so it's closed under composition.
我的意思是这是组合所以
I mean this is the composition so
二元运算符，我们要组合这些数字。
binary operators, we're gonna compose these numbers.
所以现在，让我们继续说，我们要取几个数字的乘积。
So now, let's go ahead and say, we’re gonna take the product of a few numbers.
那么二、五和八怎么样。
So how about two and five and eight.
再说一次，它是关联的，对吗？
And again, it’s associative right?
我如何将这个操作括起来并不重要。
It doesn’t matter how I parenthesize this operation.
再次，它是关闭的。
And again, it is closed.
在我得到产品的数据类型下。
Under the data type I'm getting the product of.
现在，对比作为一个反例，如果，
Now, contrast just as a counter example, if,
假设我有 10 除以 4 除以 2。
let's say I have 10 divided by 4 divided by 2.
这既不是封闭的也不是关联的。
This is neither closed nor associative.
所以如果我做四比二，我会得到两个，对吧？
So if I do four over two, I'm gonna get two, right?
然后 10 除以 2 是 5。
And then 10 divided by two is five.
所以有那个答案，但如果我加括号
So there's that answer but if I parenthesized
这样 10 比 4 就像 2.5。
it this way 10 over 4 is like 2.5.
并且不超过两个就像 1.2。
And that not over two is like, 1.2.
是的，所以我们将整数分解为浮点数
And it's, so we're breaking out of integers into floats and
我们得到了不同的答案，但这取决于我们如何加括号。
we're getting different answers but depending on how we parenthesize.
就像仅供参考，如果你是封闭的并且你是联想的，那么你就是平行的。
Just as FYI, if you're closed and you're associative, you're parallel.
这很整洁。
That's pretty neat.
你可以并行化，
You can parallelize that,
你可以把它分成一堆不同的添加物，对吧？
you can chunk it up into a bunch of different additions, right?
x 加 y 加 z。
x plus y plus z.
我们可以将它发送到不同的服务器，将它们全部组合起来
We can send it to different servers have them all combined and
然后合并结果。
then combine the results.
我们可以并行执行。
And we can do it in parallel.
那太棒了。
That's pretty great.
拼写关联错误，但无论如何。
Spelled associative wrong, but whatever.
让我们看更多这方面的例子。
Let's look at more examples of this.
假设我们有一个真、一个真和一个假。
Let's say we have a true and a true and a false.
这又是联想的。
This is again associative.
我们可以做 ORS，这与我们只是在看这些二进制文件有关
We could do ORS, that's associated with we're just looking at these binary
运算符，它们是关联的，它们是封闭的。
operators they are associative and they are closed.
这有什么关系，如何设置交集，我们有 1、2、3。
There's something to this, how about set intersection, we have 1, 2, 3.
我们将进行会面，那不是真正的接线员。
And we'll do the meet, that's not a real operator.
我只是为了弥补这一点。
I'm just making that up for this.
我们有 2, 5, 6 并再次这样做，我们可以，本质上这是关联的，
We have 2, 5, 6 and do that again, we could, essentially that's associative,
我们会得到所有数组的交集，对吧？
we'll get the intersection of all the arrays, right?
所以在这种情况下，它会是两个但是，让我们深入到这个路口或工会。
So in this case, it'd be two but, let's go down to this junction or union.
你得到同样的东西。
You get the same thing.
你得到了他们所有人的联合。
You get the union of all them.
这是关联的，它是封闭的。
This is associative, it's closed.
所以试着想想半群的任何其他例子，就是这样
So try to think of any other examples of a semigroup, that's that's
我们得到的是任何一种- &gt;&gt; 关闭又是什么意思？
what we're getting at is any kind of- &gt;&gt; What does closed mean again?
&gt;&gt; 关闭意味着我们在，如果我要到达十字路口或
&gt;&gt; Close means that we're, if I'm going to get the intersection or
这些集合的并集，在这种情况下，我会得到一个新的集合或数组。
union of these sets, I'll get a new set back or array in this case.
整数也是一样。
Same thing with integers.
我不改变数据类型。
I don't change the data type.
当我们查看除法时，我知道在 JavaScript 中只是数字。
When we looked at division, I know in JavaScript is just number.
但是我们有整数，我们将整数和繁荣相除，你得到一个浮点数或
But we had integers and we were dividing integers and boom, you get a float or
你不知从哪里得到一个实数，对，所以它不会被关闭。
you get a real number out of nowhere, right and so that is not closed.